Siqi Wu

Canberra, ACT, Australia | siqi.wu@anu.edu.au | http://users.cecs.anu.edu.au/~siqi.wu/

SUMMARY

I will join the School of Information at University of Michigan as a research fellow in 2021. I am currently a research fellow in the Computational Media Lab at Australian National University. My work lies in the fields of computational social science and social computing.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow Australian National University. Canberra, ACT, Australia	2020.09 – present
- Computational Media Lab. Adviser: Lexing Xie.	
Visiting Research Assistant University of Michigan. Remote due to COVID-19	2020.05 — present
- Center for Social Media Responsibility, Adviser: Paul Respick	

EDUCATION

Australian National University. Canberra, ACT, Australia

2016.06 - 2020.09

- PhD in Computer Science. Advisers: Lexing Xie and Marian-Andrei Rizoiu.
- Thesis: Measuring collective attention in online content: Sampling, engagement, and network effects.

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, VIC, Australia

2013.07 - 2015.07

- Master of Information Technology. Adviser: Richard Sinnott.
- Thesis: An architecture for big data processing and visualisation of traffic data.

Tianjin University. Tianjin, China

2008.09 - 2012.06

- Bachelor of Electronics Engineering.

PUBLICATIONS

- 8. AttentionFlow: Visualising influence in networks of time series Shin*, Tran*, **Wu***, Mathews, Wang, Lyall, and Xie. *WSDM* '21. Demo.
- 7. Unsupervised cyberbullying detection via time-informed Gaussian mixture model Cheng, Shu, **Wu**, Silva, Hall, and Liu. *CIKM* '20. Full paper, AR=21%.
- 6. Variation across scales: Measurement fidelity under Twitter data sampling **Wu**, Rizoiu, and Xie. *ICWSM* '20. Full paper, AR=17%.
- 5. Estimating attention flow in online video networks
 - Wu, Rizoiu, and Xie. CSCW '19. Full paper, best paper honourable mention, top 5%, AR=31%.
- 4. How is attention allocated? Data-driven studies of popularity and engagement in online videos **Wu**. *WSDM* '19. Doctoral consortium.
- 3. Beyond views: Measuring and predicting engagement in online videos **Wu**, Rizoiu, and Xie. *ICWSM* '18. Full paper, AR=16%.
- 2. Will this video go viral? Explaining and predicting the popularity of YouTube videos Kong, Rizoiu, **Wu**, and Xie. WWW '18. Demo.
- 1. SMASH: A cloud-based architecture for big data processing and visualization of traffic data **Wu**, Morandini, Sinnott. *DSDIS* '15. Full paper.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | MicroStrategy, Inc. Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China

2015.09 - 2016.05

- Big Data Engine team. Built Apache Spark alike engine to process massive data.

Software Developer Intern | Baidu, Inc. Beijing, China

2014.12 - 2015.02

- Baidu Maps team. Developed a tool to collect realtime traffic status.

AWARDS

- ANU Postgraduate Research Scholarship '20
- ANU VC Travel Grant '20
- Google PhD Fellowship '18
- ICWSM Student Travel Scholarship '18
- NICTA PhD Scholarship '16-'19
- NICTA Research Project Award '16-'19
- ANU HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship '16-'20

TEACHING

- Teaching Assistance in graduate course COMP6490 Document analysis ('17, '18).
- Teaching Assistance in undergraduate course COMP1030 Art of computing ('17).

COMMUNITY SERVICE

- Reviewer: ICWSM ('17, '18, '21), CSCW ('19, '20, '21), WWW ('19, '20), AAAI ('19), TOIS ('20)

RESOURCES

- Softwares: Twitter-intact-stream, YouTube-insight.
- Datasets: Complete/sampled retweet cascades, Vevo music graph, YouTube engagement '16.

MISC.

- Organizing: co-organized the Computational Media Lab winter workshop '19.
- Certificates: 16 MOOC courses, e.g., machine learning, social network analysis, algorithms, etc.
- Running: 18 100+km events, 50+ ultra marathons finisher, 2:57 marathon.